[Music]
you're listening to the AI native Dev
brought to you by
Tesla on today's episode we're trying to
categorize AI development tools uh to
really better map out the space of AI
native software development and we will
later Deep dive into each of these
categories uh in some of our content
including podcast and blog and other
places we're going to learn and
understand about each of these topics in
depth understand what developers and
various teams and organizations should
be thinking about in the AI tooling
ecosystem overall and perhaps make sure
they understand what coverage they need
across the various categories as well
that should help frame the discussions
going forward first of all why don't we
introduce our wonderful our wonderful
guest Amir shvat Amir how are you good
thank you for having me how are you
doing absolutely complely ENT I'm doing
very well thank you and to introduce you
Amir it was funny actually because I
mentioned you on the on the last episode
of the podcast rather the first episode
of the podcast to guy and I thought
actually there's so much that I could
say about Amir in terms of your
experiences the places you've worked at
and I thought actually I wonder how Amir
would like to be introduced tell us Amir
of all the amazing things going from
maybe it's twitch or maybe it's some of
the work that you did at Twitter maybe
it's the investment that you do how how
does one introduce air sh up thank you
yes I have a very builtin introduction
that I do every time if you heard me
once I apologize because it's very
repetitive I've turned to the dark side
about a year ago I'm a investor I've
done a little bit of like Angel
investment at that about 35 Angel
Investments and then turned to the dark
side in Earnest and I invest in
developer Tools in my career I've been a
one-trick pony I've been in developer
Tools in my entire career started
Microsoft in the era of net not yet if
you remember that then went to Google
worked on Chrome on Cloud on Android
worked on a startup program for Google
then joined a small startup called slack
it was two weeks before we launched the
platform and left when we had 250,000
weekly active developers then joined
twitch it was a lot of fun working with
game developers connecting between
twitch which is a streaming platform for
gamers and Riot and blizzard and EA and
all that cool stuff then created my own
startup called reshuffle which got
acquired by Twitter so Jack dorsy bought
my company and then Elon closed the apis
True Believer in open platform and open
apis for developers yeah absolutely well
I what an illustrious career so far it's
great to have you on board and I thinkir
when I think about that who would be a
great person to talk about AI Dev tools
and categorize them you're top of the
list really in thinking thinking about
how to position the various Dev tools
and it's important to be able to
categorize things is really important
right to be able to understand because
people are thinking how do we use Ai and
get AI into our processes what should
people be thinking about and I think
categorizing them gives people that
ability to say look these are the areas
I want to focus on first I recognize
these other categories or areas we could
invest in but let's be a bit strategic
and let's prioritize where we should
introduce AI do you feel that's how
people think about that does it help
definitely I think that we we have so
many piics and shovels creators right
now people will help you with this
people will help you with that and I
think as someone who creates code you
need to understand where is my biggest
difficulty where is my biggest challenge
where is the thing that are mind dained
that I don't want to do every day that I
can offload to these tools to be a lot
more productive and you can see
companies from Enterprise to small
startups using AI to develop so it gives
you an edge you just need to choose
where you need that edge H absolutely
and I think what we're going to be doing
is once we create these categories we
will have deep dive sessions in all of
these to say okay what should we be
thinking about and let's go deep into
those so yeah the more you say today
Amir the more work you're creating for
me but don't let that stop you
suggesting categories when we think
about categories is there a way we
should do this should we be doing it by
function whether it's a testing thing or
something should we do it by stlc where
we say okay should we let's do the
development phase let's do the pipeline
phase how do people think about thises
does it matter so I I think you could
look at it from like the P development
phase I think we've picked major areas
where we see a lot of innovation
happening and we see companies that we
really like in creating work for you
maybe creating some work work for me
maybe we can get some of these Founders
to come and speak in this show and talk
in about these major areas I think the
key the way I look at it as an engineer
is where do I feel the pain the most
what are the things that are repetitive
that are not creative in my life as a
developer and where can I plug in Ai and
and I think that's a category we should
follow at least in this session and
we're not covering all of these we had a
lot of brainstorming and thought about a
lot of categories but we'll choose the
main categories and we'd love to hear
from the audience if there's like new
categories that they're thinking about
so this is the beginning of a community
conversation absolutely yeah we're not
providing Solutions just yet we're
trying to understand the questions so
this is a absolutely an open
conversation so we'd love to hear if we
should merge categories if we should if
there are major things we're missing and
so forth so Amir what should our first
category be what's the one top of your
list so I think the top category is the
category that is being used the most
today I when I'm talking to developers
this is the number one AI enablement
that they're seeing and that's code
completion tools whether it's co-pilot
there's also tab n which I'm an investor
in these are tools that are integrated
created into your IDE and they're like
the extension of what used to be like
the tab tab or like the ability to auto
complete a lot of the functions or do
refactoring when I was a Java developer
I used to do a lot of refactoring and
because Java is very verbose the ID
helps you and understands what are the
things that you need to do refactoring
so I see this as a evolution of that so
basically you use the IDE and you have a
co-pilot or you have a tab n that
integrates into your ID and helps you
write significant amount of code so a
lot of the blueprints a lot of the table
Stakes code is done by the AI and you
could do just the tweaking just the
checking and just the writing the
business logic that is unique in your
brain and a lot of people's mileage
varies on this one right in terms of
you'll get different developers that
will say oh my gosh this is insane it's
so good it saves me so much time
productiv wise or or learning about apis
they don't know exactly where to start
in a co-pilot or tab 9 or a Cod whatever
it is is telling me what the next thing
I should write when I've actually just
got an empty page straight away other
developers will say you know what it's
always generating code in a way I don't
like or in different style is this
something that we just need to get used
to is it something the LMS need to get
better at how mature would you say we
are in the code completion tooling
category today so I think the AI will
evolve to be more uh personalized um but
I think it's at the end of the day if
you like everything handcrafted you
would not like what AI will create for
you it is very hard for AI to use you as
the data sample and create code in your
image I think you'll need to understand
that this is just like uh blueprint it
will have its own opinionated way of of
writing the code tab N9 is slightly less
opinion or like adheres to the company's
best practices by training on the
company's data set so if you and
co-pilot is more like general purpose
data set which is all the code that's in
GitHub but if you want to um maybe train
a little bit on your own company's data
set on the way you do things then tab n
might be uh the right solution and maybe
we'll see a solution where the co-pilot
understands how you write code and maybe
uses you as a training set but I think
it's a smaller training set so it will
never be as accurate as the way you
wanted to write the code yeah really
interesting and it's actually worth
looking at the various different types
of of tools in this category right
because they're all subtly different
like you mentioned there I think is it
Tav 9 as well that have an has an
offline mode I can't remember tab it is
tab n right so I think you you
effectively download that model and
you're actually running that model
locally on your environment so if you're
on a train or on a flight or whatever or
just coding alone somewhere in a cave
you can effectively still use that
offline which is very interesting yeah
it's and and code Whisperer another one
really good for Amazon AWS style if you
work with AWS Services it's particularly
good in in those kind of spaces pulling
towards the AWS apis and things like
that so yeah really worth that do you
see people
today I guess one of the things that guy
and I were talking about last week was
about the the difference between AI
assisted and AI native and I think AI
assisted is more that we're in that same
workflow and this tool is making me
faster in that same workflow whereas AI
native is perhaps a little bit more okay
how we changing the way we work because
we're thinking about AI at its core I
guess some the ways that you use each of
these tools can lean into both depending
on if you're writing one line or if
you're writing a function or or a
snippet or if you're writing a module
right so H how do you see people using
this mostly today how do you see it
happening going forward so yes and and
we'll see as we go through the
categories some of these are going to
move more towards the agent model yes
where we're moving from the assistant
the co-pilot model to an autopilot model
and there are certain aspects of coding
and not just coding but for example
testing and other things where you want
to have someone not just helping you but
maybe taking the entire task all
together so I think that you're very
right we're going to see like a movement
from an auto co-pilot that helps you
maybe do small things maybe refactor
maybe do migrations and stuff like that
all the way to developers offloading
tasks to these agents and then changing
the way we actually do things and I
think it also ties to the tools so all
these co-pilots live inside your IDE
because they're not changing the way
you're working they're not changing your
daytoday but as we move towards a
collaborative approach it will be it's
called synthetic humans I think Ryan
Hoover from product hunt uh coin that
what are the synthetic humans that we
can have in our engineering team that
could do the boring things that humans
don't want to do uh and we'll see more
and more o of these as time passes yeah
is it fair to say as well that in this
category you're pretty much seeing new
tools whether it's from startups or
existing companies it's not really
repurposing existing tools maybe we'll
see in some of the later categories but
these are purpose built tools for this
category 100% so what's our next
category which you okay so our next
category is something that I am really
passionate about because as a developer
I was I was developing during the test
driven development if you remember that
stage I'm sure a lot of Engineers are
still big Believers in that and that's
the text test then generation era or
tools so what can AI help me to generate
the test to do better performance better
penetration testing but also like just
testing all the code to see that it
meets the the testing criteria so here
we have codium leading the charge a lot
of developers are using it we're also
seeing heel which is another company I
invested in and heel takes a blackbox
approach so you create your website and
then you give heel dodev URL and it acts
as a blackbox tester for those of you
who don't know blackbox tester is a
tester that looks at the site without
having any knowledge of the codebase so
they just go and they start pressing on
buttons and seeing what is performant
what is not performant how does the
login flow go maybe there's edge cases
in the inputs so these are the types of
AI Solutions and if you ever been in
testing you know how hard these type of
tests are as an engineer you're often
blind to all the tests that you need to
create because you build a certain set
of code for a certain set of of
functionality but when you put it on in
the real world you see everybody's using
or abusing your code in a in a very
different way than what you wanted being
able to see all the edge cases and being
able to use your code in a way that you
haven't thought about and finding all
the bugs is a great use for AI because
it could actually look at all the
permutations of all the inputs and and
do a lot of interesting thing from pen
testing to just generating unit tests I
think this is where AI could be
extremely useful in an area that is
extremely boring and extremely
tedious yeah and I think it's
interesting actually because you look at
something like co- completion that we
just talked about and you get a lot of
developers that are like oh my gosh is
this going to take my job this going to
take my job I'm I'm worried that it's
taking the thing that I love away you
look at something like test generation
and other than those folks who are
heavily into tdd live and breathe tdd
who who want to write their tests and
want to build functionality that makes
those tests pass um test is is very
often one of those things get that get
squeezed or that developers don't want
to do that much and and it it often ends
ends up with functionality that hasn't
been tested effectively or have been so
lightly golden path tested that like you
say these edge cases and and things that
just aren't covered so this is something
that could actually really improve the
quality of our applications today
because they're done properly and
thoroughly right AI is not lazy so it it
will do a thorough job on on this this
is could be a real game changer for
super Game Changer I can tell you from
my experience as a product leader the
most most important flow is often not
tested by most developers which is the
onboarding flow yes most developers
create a website and then you can log
into that website you log in once you
don't need to log in again so most
developers when they test their solution
when they're taste when they test their
SAS they actually don't go through the
work for the onboarding flow again and
when that onboarding flow breaks or it's
not comfortable or it's I don't know
there's a new browser and there's no new
standard and and it doesn't adhere to
that standard the developers are almost
always blind to that flow yeah and going
through onboarding again every day to
make sure that it's good it's very
tedious I don't know any developer that
wants to do that but to your point AI
will never get bored and so that's a
great boring task that we can offload to
to AI that will say hey there's a new
standard there's a new I don't know
something in your flow that could
improve in a flow that nobody tests yeah
let's play devil's advocate for a second
though because
one of the things that is extremely
frustrating for developers who have
tests that a run maybe fail and they
look at the test and they think oh come
on this test is absolute BS right it's a
it's a false positive is wasting my time
all of a sudden me coming from a
security my previous job from a develop
a security background false positives
were like the it was the bin of
everyone's existence right as a
developer like security coming with all
these tests that actually
maybe don't mean anything or aren't
really exploitable how mature is the AI
test generation specifically so that we
don't actually just add all this in and
then really frustrate developers is this
something that's that we could and
should be adding in now so I think from
what I'm hearing from developers it's
pretty useful and it's because it's not
automated because it's not like will
create every permutation of the test
it's more AI driven in terms of I know
what current tests were run on this type
of code so I'll generate in that area I
think the tests that you're getting are
pretty good what you need to see is that
it has completion that it actually is
covering the use cases that you're
trying to do and I'm sure there's going
to be false positives just to to add to
the devil Advocates action a developer
that doesn't use their own code to test
it do not develop customer passion for
it so for example if you're building an
SDK it could pass all the tests
but it's still a sucky experience let's
say your o requires 15 parameters and
nobody really wants to use it because of
that AI would probably not say hey your
login function sucks because it has 15
parameters this is something that you
will need to do so I still encourage
developers to even if you have all these
taste test capabilities dog food so use
your own code in order to see that it
actually is delightful for cust
customers yeah and the and the
developers leaning in not necessarily to
the level of the code but to the level
of the test cases that are actually
being written exctly so that they can
say yeah I can visibly see the coverage
based on the use cases not coverage
based on the lines of branches and
things like that let let's we'll let the
tooling work that out and make sure it
generates that but I now care about the
business Logic the you the coverage in
that respect 100% so if you create an
API it could pass all the tests but
could be a very badly constru API yeah
so also think about the meta aspect of
creating our craft needs to be good
right it needs to be delightful it needs
to be connected and have a good service
between developers automated tests are
still not there in terms of making sure
that the code is 100% delightful and
it's our job to do that yeah amazing
amazing two categories so far code
completion okay so let's move to the
next category another category that I
used to love but now I'm a lazy
developer so don't love it anymore which
is code
documentation very important and the
problem is that when you write code for
the first time you might be excited and
then you create the documentation and
maybe you're like even a good writer so
you're like you're articulated and you
documented the code in a good way but
then you make a small change or someone
else makes a small change and the
documentation needs to update it so ever
worked in any Enterprise you know that
between 20 and 80 more closer to 80% of
documentation is outdated is not there
yet is uh is missing it's just like big
chunks of the documentation is not there
so I think again this is the value that
AI could bring and we'll talk about two
directions me trying to understand code
and me trying to explain code to others
uh and I think in both areas uh AI
documentation could be very useful yeah
and and actually just slightly going
back into the test point of view as well
test documentation and code are three
living streams that can very easily Veer
away from each other if they're not
updated together so I think testing as
well as documentation can can follow
that now of course testing will blow up
because it can test positive or negative
but are people writing new tests for new
functionality and I think the same kind
of like applies for those two as well
you have a great Point yes so yeah it
would be nice if the you write
documentation and then the test AI reads
that documentation understands the
meaning of what you want it to create
and then create tests in in that in that
vein so I think you're right it's all
connected and once you integrate more of
these tools and once these tools are
going to be integrated with each other
we're going to have a much more
delightful developer experience and
would you add would you add user
documentation and code documentation
together into this category so we looked
at two examples one of them is swim
which is a startup we'll share the URL
in some way but the idea is I want to
understand it's code explainability or
the ability to understand what's
happening who owns this type of code
what was the history of this code how
does this code interact with another
code so understanding the what is
happening here is a big problem and it's
a problem of documentation and swim
really helps you understand the code on
board to a new code basee train other
people on your code base this is One
Direction which is I want to understand
what is happening in the code the other
side of the commentation is I want to
explain to someone who's not technical
about what's happening what is the
product how do you configure it what are
the options maybe I'm adding
configuration in some way or maybe I
want to show how to do a flow all this
that's called the technical writing side
of code you usually have a person whose
job it is to follow the changes that are
happening in git in jira understanding
where the code needs to change a lot of
the time it's developer relations if
it's the coders related to sdks or apis
and then they need to update the
documentation whether it's client
documentation where it's whether it's
code on the website that needs to be
updated all the way to sending it to
sales and marketing to understand what's
happening in the code I think here again
AI could be very useful in becoming this
documentation as a service and there's a
company called Tata t a a TA who's
trying to understand what are the
triggers that require the commentation
change for example something happens in
your Source control something happens in
your jira something happens in slack and
how does that trigger documentation
changes on websites on many other places
yeah really interesting as well so now
we think back to that flow that you
mentioned where you know if I actually
first of all before we jump into that
intent is really different there as well
right the intent of an AI flow where
you're trying to think more as a user
from a use case point of view someone
who doesn't care about implementation
effectively they care about what do I
need to use your API for how do I use it
etc etc or or service the other it
doesn't care anywhere near as much about
the the intent of the user it's really
about the the the understanding of the
code flows and trying to prevy that back
to a developers they can more
architecturally more implementation
based understand the flows of how code
works and I really like going back to
your original point about starting with
the documentation that then writes the
tests that then writes the code that's a
really interesting way of looking at it
and when you think about how development
roles change as AI gets more established
in this space do you see the role or
almost like a developer leaning more
onto this side from the code into the
test and documentation and actually the
implementation piece the code completion
that that's more something that's that
just happens it's something that the AI
does that we don't care about we care
about this other piece because it's more
interesting and important to the
business I think if you look at my if
you analyze the job of a engineer if you
remove all the crap around meetings and
stuff like that it's about this
distilling business logic it's about
taking big problems breaking them down
to smaller problems the bigger more
complex problem go to the senior
engineers and the smaller problems go to
Junior engineers and then taking and
defining the business logic so
connecting between what humans want so
that's the PM and like defining what
does the application have and turning
that into how do actually do that with
code so I think humans are much much
better
in understanding what humans want and
then turning it into maybe a spec or
maybe some sort of architecture or maybe
some sort of a new artifact that then AI
could turn into actual code could turn
into a set of tests could turn into a
set of technical documentation so I
think humans will excel in the area
of understand what human wants I
understand what the customer wants and
now I need to create ass assets that
will help AI generate all the rests yeah
think of it as becoming a manager of AI
agents and some of these agents will do
this job and some of these agent will do
another job but you'll be the manager
because I think right now at least AI is
not good at doing that part of of
clearly understanding what humans want
and clearly breaking it down to tasks
and and capabilities and I think as a of
that and the trust differences from
where we are today and where where we
need to be that level of autonomy that
we're willing to allow within the
processes is is not where it needs to be
in order to actually get that flow but
this is the the track that I think where
a lot of people see that we're on in
terms of reaching there 100% And I think
the from my experience talking to
developers the smaller the task and more
defined the task the better AI will
perform and that's constantly I talk to
developers all the time about that if
you know how to break the task to
smaller task it is much more predictable
you'll get less hallucinations and I
don't like the word hallucinations I
think it's wrong from a technical
perspective we can deep dive to that
afterwards but you will get better
results the more the defin your AI task
is yeah awesome before we leave
documentation maturity wise is
documentation something that people
should be looking at right now trying it
out is is this something that can
actually keep track of changes and
actually provide good output does it
need more work I think documentation
actually plays on AI strong suits I
think the idea here is that AI is much
more verbose than most Engineers that I
know in terms of writing Cod and of
writing words rather than code so I
think and it's also something that AI
could really change in terms of I write
documentation for customers I I could
change my tone there versus I'm writing
for customer success so I think AI could
create a lot of assets that Engineers
just don't want to do so I'm very
bullish about AI creating the
commutation in the future yeah I love
that so the ability to almost
effectively customize the documentation
for the reader so that that's one of the
things that we always struggle with
where we as as an industry provide the
right level of documentation for for the
group but if you can do that at varying
levels in an autonomous way that that's
magic amazing okay documentation we only
at three I think we're only at three
categories we have two more that we're
going to Deep dive in and then others
that we're gonna we're gonna mention and
talk about briefly so what's your fourth
Deep dive C so the F fourth category is
uh devops there there was a shift left
and we had sres we had chat Ops if you
remember GitHub tried to coin that the
idea was hey let's not have a dedic ated
team that runs our code let's move the
responsibility towards the engineering
team that actually created the code so
for example Twitter most of the running
of the code was done by the team that
created that code and maintaining that
code in production was the
responsibility of the team that created
that service so if you had a login
service the team that was responsible
for login they made sure that the login
service is up for all the other services
there's a problem there that the problem
is that first of all you need to have a
lot of knowledge that is not around
coding so you need to have knowledge in
AWS you need to have knowledge in Google
or uh Azure you need to have knowledge
in a lot of configuration there's a lot
of complexity in running scalable
systems and Engineers already complain
and rightly so that their most of their
time is spent on meetings and
documentation and testing and all the
other things that are being there and
now they're asked to actually maintain
and run their code and wake up in the
middle of the night uh when that code
crashes so what if an AI could do that
and again this is a task that most
developers don't want to do it's a task
that is pretty repetitive if you think
about it and it's pretty mundane if you
think about it and AI could provide a
lot of value there any kind of like
startups that that catch J ey in this
space already so I the last one that
I've seen which is pretty interesting is
called resolved which what they do which
is really cool is that they tell
developers hey uh show me how you
actually deploy to production and I'll
create the playbook for that that is
repeatable so that's pretty cool the
idea is don't do things multiple times
if you ask any developer you do things
one more than two times you should
create a script for that so that what
resolved do is that they capture the way
you actually deploy to the cloud and
then every time you need to do another
deploy they create the Run book and they
know how to run it
automatically it is awesome it's still I
haven't seen and maybe I haven't looked
well enough I haven't seen my dream for
this world can I tell you my dream for
this world going then I want to actually
create a code and automatically have it
run I want to deploy to a source control
or even not a source control I want it
to run on my computer and then tell AI
make it run in the cloud and if it's
scalable make it scalable if it's not
scalable don't make it scalable and if
you ask me a few questions around like
security compliance please do that but
now it's your job to actually run that
code I think we are not far away from
that but I haven't seen anyone that
actually gives me that solution I don't
want to do devops Dev devops is
something that I think is a tax that we
have to pay yeah and I think that it's a
very interesting profession for those
who do it but for me as an engineer I
want to focus on my code I want the
minute my cicd finishes to do nothing
and then the AI will take care of it and
I want the AI to wake up in the middle
of the night when
some luckily luckily I think it's
already awake yeah maybe more awake than
we think um the more we introduce a
closer to production um we obviously
need a greater level of trust in order
to be able to do that when we put AI
left we and we're saying that I want you
to create some tests for me I want you
to write some code for me there are a
number of levels of almost Gates where
we can validate that it's done the right
thing the further we push right though
how much more trust do we need or or are
there additional mechanisms that we need
to put in place to make sure that this
wonderful new AI deployment environment
that I've just created while it's great
90% of the time 10% of the time it takes
my production down or or deploys in such
a way that actually some of my services
are unavailable what where do we need to
be and I think this is maybe more of a
people question yeah to to be able to
trust that so I I think there's that's a
very good question and I think the key
here is how much opinionated do you need
to be in order to do the devops right
because 15 years ago when I worked at
Google we had the Borg and we were
talking about self-healing systems so if
an engineer would deploy something that
is not performant the Borg itself will
roll them off right so a system a cloud
that knows how to heal itself and knows
how to roll back from Bad changes is
something that we've had for a very long
time the key is that Google was
extremely opinionated in how you develop
that code you had to use the Google
Frameworks you had to use the Google
deploy structure you had to use you had
a lot of guard rails and very
opinionated way of doing that
generalizing that problem is very hard
so building something that will do
devops for every company and every way
and every opinion and every language is
hard and up up until now not feasible
but maybe with AI and if you use the
data set in a in a well enough way you
could create a devops agent that has
trust in your environment in your type
of database in your type of language in
your type of usage pattern whether it's
B2B or b2c what type of attacks are you
going to see I think we are getting
there but we're not there yet yeah and
and other things like you mentioned if I
write code I just wanted to deploy into
the cloud for example are we creating a
greater opportunity for almost I don't
want to say hybrid cloud or something
like that but we we're when I say to
chat GPT or whatever it is copilot
whatever I want this code written and it
starts writing it I I'm starting to care
less about the
implementation if if it gets it right
when I say I want this to be deployed
are be doing this in a way whereby we're
making strategic decisions about the the
the underlying platforms and the
architectures of how things should be
deployed or or or will we do you feel
we'll get to this level where I'm like
yeah if you want to choose gcp you
choose gcp if you want to choose AWS you
choose that that's a that's more of an
implementation decision now I just care
that this is based on the inputs I have
provided of the right services that I
need you can go ahead and choose what
you want and you might actually get a
very colorful kind of different
deployment based on the decisions it
wants to make is is this a possible
future do you think or do you think
people will really still want to keep
their Stacks similar and and use AI to
deploy onto that similar stack I I think
it depends on the workload that you're
trying to build for example if I want to
build a website I don't care which
language you do maybe I'm opinionated
about react versus versus view but I
don't care about the details of which I
don't know UI framework you chose or
something like that or what are the
parameters that are passed between the
single page app and the server side I
don't care about that I just want a page
and if it's for marketing I just I want
it to look nice so I would love to talk
to CH GPT and say hey create a website
already deploy it here's my domain do
all the DNS magic that devops do and
deploy that website that will be amazing
and I think companies like Wix are
trying to do that so that's on the very
very lightweight workloads if I'm doing
server to server very complex very high
throughput very opinionated set of apis
let's say I'm building re revamping
stripe API I want to be very opinionated
so the more complex and more Mission
critical the workload the workloads are
you will want to have more deeper
understanding so like most developers
don't know the difference between or
don't care between UDP and TCP they just
want information to to move from one
computer to the other but some low like
very hardcore develop ERS actually are
very opinionated whether to use a UDP or
a TCP depending on the infrastructure
and the tasks so I think the the the
task will Define how opinionated you
want to be if that makes sense yeah no
absolutely um okay let's jump on to the
fifth and and final category that we're
going to Deep dive on and then we'll
then we'll mention the others in the
list as well yes we're talking about AI
monitoring and debugging this is I think
going back now to a to a co-pilot era
where you want your you worked on your
code you deployed it and now you want to
get insights into how that code performs
and what's wrong with the code uh we
used to have tools for forever uh
there's also interesting companies in
this area like digma that look at uh
your data in production and pull that
into your IDE U but I think AI could
help here as well the company that I've
seen in this area that is pretty
interesting is second dodev and they
help you maintain the code and also do
migration of code for example if you
want to move from an Old Co code set
into a new code set they could help you
do that and that I form this under the
area of after I've written the code I
need to check that it's running okay
debug when it's not running okay and
maybe improve it through maintenance uh
and all of these are tasks that will be
um aided by AI in the future so that's
the major category here and this is this
is quite a little bit different to for
example if we was to compare contrast
this to the code completion the code
suggestion style category whereas the
the the code suggestion category are
pretty much entirely all new tools new
players and startups or or or new tools
from existing companies here with AO
monitoring is already a busy space we're
probably going to see a lot lot of
existing Monitoring Solutions with AI
functionality but there's going to be a
lot of space here for for new startups
as well right 100% I think we're going
to see up until now we've seen a lot of
automatic and semi-automatic debugging
and monitoring tools and I think this is
an area where AI could use a lot of the
patterns and take that as a training set
to see what's a normal day look like and
then give you insights into monitoring
and debugging of like hey this is
irregular yeah so I think that there's a
interesting area of like an AI looks at
your traffic patterns and understands
what's a good day and maybe it goes
through a year so there's like in
Christmas you get more Shoppers and more
people so it's not a Dos in Christmas
it's actually actual human usage but
then if you train it well enough and you
give it enough data it knows how to look
at irregular things it knows how to flag
the right things you remember you told
you talked about um false positives
monitoring has a lot of false positives
right so how do you help AI understand
what is actually a monitoring event and
what is not a monitoring event so I
think AI will become a lot better there
but I have no doubt that we will use AI
because it's like I don't know if it's
an llm but it's definitely a big data
problem yeah this feels like a little
bit of a less mature space in terms of
AI tooling is that fair or would you say
there are tools that you you should be
looking out or this is an area that you
absolutely should be looking at right
now does it need to develop more I think
it needs to develop more I think the
incumbents are trying to uh to to
innovate there and again I think we
talked about it in the beginning of this
session and like where does the pain
rely the most I think right now the pain
is in like the development the testing
the documentation and I think and
debugging and monit touring we'll see a
lot of innovation but it will follow
after we we get more trust in AI so we
done the five deep Dives let's describe
the remaining categories that you and
this is like a not a super set this is a
subset of all the things that we can
think about and we're totally open to
community uh feedback on this so we are
talking about what does the cicd of this
world look like in Ai and how can I
create better cicd or like developer
workflow Tool uh with a yach triaging
having a better ation doing PRS all of
that good stuff there's one company that
I've seen that is pretty interesting
pseudo that is in that area AI code
explainer we talked about this a little
bit but we think that there's a big
opportunity to innovate there I want to
be able to better read the code I want
to be able to better change the code in
an easy way performance tooling so
there's uh a company called uh code FL
code uh flash that we'll talk about a
little later but how can I do better
performance I spent six months 10 years
ago trying to make some Java code more
performant it was fun for the first
three months and then it became very
painful to go Section by section for
each piece of the code and make it more
performant very time consuming task so
maybe AI could help there and it's a
data heavy space as well right so so
it's a potentially a good space there to
to find anomali yeah absolutely and
there's AI for security tooling AI for
ux as a backend engineer I understand
nothing about user experience so maybe
there's a AI that could help me build
nice front ends code reviews very useful
wouldn't it be cool we actually did that
at slack we had one of our best
Engineers he was very good at doing code
reviews we looked at his code reviews
and created an AI bot that copied him
that did the same test that he does
every time and with with with a lot of
the tools that that that you've
mentioned in the like before as well
with the code explainer the code testing
the code documentation code review
should actually be a ton easier when
when you've effectively got all of this
largely done for you but also very well
explained as well 100% so I'd love to
see a code reviewer and then there's
data management all the things that you
do with your databases or your local
storage or any or S3 any type of data
would be interesting as a category and
the last thing that we wanted to talk
about is the autonomous agents yeah uh
that's Devon with their video that blew
the internet for a while and will we
have an actual set of that's the that's
maybe the the mission for our world in
terms of creating agents that could
create code maybe it's not maybe it's
just a dream that people have right now
but we think the direction of where this
is going is moving from a co-pilot to an
autopilot and whether Devon is real or
not and how useful it is it's the jury
is still out there but I think we will
have a world where at least some of the
tasks are going to be automated by this
junior AI developer friend that you have
and that's the autonomous agents
category and how do you have a team team
of both humans and AI Engineers working
together to complete a task yeah I'll
also have a shout out here to a company
uh crew aai who I've used quite a bit
now um they're a bold start company
actually and and they're they're a
company that um effectively build that
framework whereby you can create a crew
of agents and each agent effectively has
this backstory has this you can have
developers you can have have code
reviews you can have people with various
backgrounds and they're looking their
tasks that they you can have a number of
tasks that each of these agents can
perform and they're looking at things in
a different way and I think when you
know as you were saying when you break
something down into smaller pieces and
and the agents are very laser focused on
doing a small thing in a specific way
they're actually pretty good at it and
and and if you chain these agents
together you actually get far stronger
results than if you was just to go to a
g a plane GPT and just ask for something
generic and it provide it spits one
answer out doing this agent flow is is
far better so i' definitely recommend
people take a look at those kind of
things and crew AI was what I played
with and used I love crei I think
they're awesome there's also code flash
so that's you know how in every team
there's this grumpy old guy that does
the performance for everyone he said
like this code is great but if you do
this tweaks it could be much more
performant I used to have that I used to
have that guy and then I used to become
that guy being giving to all my
team for not code basically code flash
that's what they do they look at the
code they generate the test and then
they are the person they are the
synthetic human that posts PRS to
improve your code uh and I think again
we will see different aspects of these
agents as we move forward amazing that
that wraps up our our categories I'm
sure we've missed some I'm sure some
will grow into more important categories
and others maybe not so important but
this is where we are learning so um yeah
would' love to hear from folks what
categories you feel we missed what
categories you're most excited about if
there are certain categories that are
super high priority would love to know
which ones they are and we'll dig into
these but next up is the code completion
category so we're going to we're going
to take a look into that and in fact we
will be talking to uh the folks at tab n
look forward to that one next yeah this
is a work in progress tell us podcast at
T .io would love to hear from you or why
not on Twitter or other platforms yeah
let us know how we get on Amir wonderful
conversation as always thank you very
much had a lot of fun in chatting and
appreciate all of your all of your
wonderful experience and thoughts thank
you for having me this was
[Applause]
fun thanks for tuning in join us next
time on the AI native Dev brought to you
by Tesla
[Music]